mycanvas.com 2015-04-07

# Privacy Statement | MyCanvas.com | Freedom of Expression

This Privacy Statement was last updated on July 6, 2009.   
If you have not reviewed it since that date, please do so.   
You will not receive any other notice of changes to this statement.

## Privacy Information for MyCanvas.com

Ancestry.com Operations Inc., ("Ancestry.com", "Ancestry", "we", "our" or "us") operator of this Website, recognizes the confidentiality of information that may be disclosed by members in registering or making purchases from our Website and we are committed to protecting your privacy. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for this Website. 

The specifics of our use of personal information are best described in the answers to the following Frequently Asked Questions: 

## Do you ask for personal information from your members?

Yes. We ask for your name, e-mail address, and other limited personal information when you sign up as a member, when you use features such as e-mail, and when you make purchases from us. We may ask for similar information at other times, such as when you enter sweepstakes or other promotions sponsored by us and/or one of our partners. To facilitate payment and fulfillment in connection with membership and other purchases from us, we will request personal credit card, debit card, or other payment information.

As a member of MyCanvas.com, you can also chose to share your project with others, which will make any information about you in that project public to those with whom you share or with whom they may share your project. You should use discretion in with whom and how you share your project.

## How do you use my personal information?

The primary use of your personal information, other than directly in connection with a purchase, is to efficiently provide you with personalized, relevant information. 

We will also use registration information to let you know about new features or other offers of interest from us and to address customer service needs and requests. 

In distributing advertiser or sponsor messages, the advertiser is not given access to individual account information. We do not sell, rent, or otherwise distribute the personal information you provide us to these advertisers for their use. Advertisers simply provide the advertising message and we then display the ad to appropriate users. 

## Will you disclose any of my personal information to third parties?

We will not disclose your personal information provided in connection with membership registration or purchases, except as described in this Privacy Statement or as may be required by law, or to protect our rights or property.

Information submitted by you online (such as information about products you purchase from us, your name, address, e-mail address) may be shared with companies with which we have a commercial relationship and through which you reached MyCanvas.com, for marketing purposes. For example, if you make a purchase with us because of an offer made through another Website acting as a distributor of our products, in that circumstance you will be considered their customer as well. We will not, except as may be required by law, share with any other party your password or payment information. 

Other circumstances where limited personal information may be disclosed are specifically described when the data is collected, or in the rules of sweepstakes or other promotions. 

We do reserve the right to disclose aggregated user statistics, such as "45 percent of our users are female" or "10,000 members indicate an interest in gardening" in order to describe our services to prospective partners, advertisers, and other third parties. 

Under protection of confidentiality agreements, we use third party processors in some cases to help us provide services and manage our Websites and relationships with you. These may include purchase and order fulfillment, credit card processing, removing duplicate information from lists, providing marketing assistance and providing other customer services. Third-party processors and providers will be given access only to that information needed to perform their support functions, and are prohibited from using it for other purposes. 

As our business continues to grow, we might buy or sell subsidiaries or business units. In these transactions, customer information is often one of the transferred assets, remaining subject to promises made in existing privacy statements. Also, in the event that Ancestry, or substantially all of its assets are acquired, customer information will, as a matter of course, be one of the transferred assets. 

## What about purchases from advertisers or other linked Websites?

If you click away from MyCanvas.com to visit the Website of any third party advertiser or sponsor, you may be asked for your credit card or other personal information in order to purchase or use products and services offered. These companies have their own privacy and data collection practices. We have no responsibility or liability for these independent policies. You should therefore review their privacy policies carefully if you have concerns about how your information may be used. 

## Will you use my information for direct mailings?

We will send electronic mail or other mail to you, for the purpose of informing you of changes or additions to MyCanvas.com, or of any MyCanvas.com or Ancestry related products and services. If you do not want to receive such mailings, you may opt out at any time by using the unsubscribe link listed in the e-mail or by amending your "newsletter and email preferences" in the "My Account" section of the site.

## May I refuse to provide personal information to you or to accept advertising?

Visitors may access MyCanvas.com’s services by providing a first name, last name, and e-mail address or other information that we may deem appropriate to that purpose. Because the MyCanvas.com Website is partially advertiser supported, you may not "turn off" the advertising that appears on MyCanvas.com pages, but you may opt to be excluded from any e-mail advertising. 

## Do you use "IP Addresses" and cookies?

## IP Addresses:

We do use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server, and to administer our Website. Your IP address is also used to gather broad demographic information such as geographic distribution of our members and may be used to “geolocate” our members to allow us to provide services appropriate to your place of residence. 

## Cookies:

Contrary to popular myth, cookies do not extract private or personal information from your computer’s memory, but rather, record only information you volunteer to us upon registering or visiting the Website. Cookies are tiny files placed onto the hard drive of your computer when you register at our Website that enable our server to recognize or "remember" who you are each time you return. We may make limited use of cookies to deliver content specific to your interests. For instance, we may use cookies to retain your personal preferences, hold session information for a "shopping basket," or save your password so it doesn’t have to be re-entered each time you login. 

You can delete or block cookies from your computer if you want to (your browser help function should tell you how to do this), but certain MyCanvas services may not work correctly or at all if you delete and/or block cookies.

## Advertiser Cookies:

We may use third-party advertising companies to serve ads on our behalf. These companies may employ cookies and action tags (also known as single pixel gifs or web beacons) to measure advertising effectiveness. Any information that these third parties collect via cookies and action tags is completely anonymous. [If you would like more information about this practice and your choices, click here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/optout_nonppii.asp). Ancestry uses the Tacoda Audience Network (TAN) to serve targeted advertising. [If you wish to opt-out from TAN and other offerings, click here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/optout_nonppii.asp).

## Contests & Promotions

We may occasionally run contests or other special promotions on our Website in which we ask members or visitors for contact information (like an e-mail address) or demographic information (like a zip code, age, or income level). We use this data to send users promotional material about our company or our partners. The participant’s contact information is also used to contact him or her when necessary and may be shared with other companies for promotional purposes, but only with your prior permission and under the terms and conditions specified when you take part in the promotion. At any time, you may opt-out of receiving future mailings of this kind, or simply decline to take part in the promotions. 

## Contacting Us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Statement, the practices of or your dealings with this Website, you may contact us at the following address:  
Ancestry.com   
Attn: Customer Solutions   
360 W. 4800 N.  
Provo, UT 84604
